well I thank you so much for your fourth
visit for the fourth visit on RMG's
Rimes reasons and we appreciate very
much what you do we are talking to
ladies and gentlemen John kiraku former
CIA officer and whistleblower who told
us about the enhanced tear I mean
torture program of the US government and
when I read your story I made sure that
I wrote several pieces about it and I
made sure that and I made sure that the
public could come to at least a somewhat
of an understanding of the sacrifices
that you and your family may and still
makes to this day and and sacrifices
that all whistleblowers make when they
go against the big bad the biggest
baddest bully on the block US government
so what I'm gonna do today John it's not
gonna pick your brain about some of the
things we see taking place right now
yeah and so there has been this
narrative that because it seems that the
deep state isn't that in love with
Donald Trump that son Donald Trump is
the champion of the people that they go
to this dichotomy that it the deep state
hates you then you're a good guy if the
deep state likes you then you're a bad
guy
so this dichotomy they have where
there's no nuance with this where we
can't walk and chew gum at the same time
give me your insights on because I know
you've paid attention to this as well
you know your insights on this house me
how do you
I've actually written about this a
couple of times this is something that's
funny to me because so many Americans
feel like they have to choose a side
mm-hmm if you're anti-trump you have to
be Pro CIA and FBI and conversely if you
if you are pro Trump that you have to be
anti CIA and FBI you know you can have a
scenario where there's just simply no
good guy it should all be ashamed of
themselves
there really is a deep state it probably
is trying to take down this president
but that doesn't mean that the president
deserves our support and in those
ridings
what do you attribute to this need to
have to embrace one or the other yeah I
mean what do you attribute that to
is it the partisan nonsense we've been
going through since oh I don't know
forever I mean yeah in part I think that
it is part of the abject partisanship
that we seem to find ourselves in and in
part you know I think I think it's a
part of human nature mm-hmm to want to
have your own views validated mm-hmm and
so we tend to seek out like-minded
people we tend to seek out people who
have the same core beliefs that we have
in the same political analysis that we
espouse and it's easier to do that and
probably more dangerous to do that
because of the advent of social media
you know so many of us have Facebook
pages or Instagram or Twitter and we
want people to like our posts or to
reach eight or to share because it
validates us and it makes us it makes us
think that we're right and and and in
some way it makes sense out of it a very
chaotic world yeah that you know that
that somehow is I've been validated
through this
I mean I've never understood that now
those of us who use the Internet and
social media to do the work that we do
to make impact not just trying to get
more likes or get more followers but to
make impact I think that sometime I
think that sometimes there's a this thin
line between okay wanting to be liked
and really one just wanting to make an
impact because sometimes those do get
completed yeah that that there are
people who do have a lot of followers
because they are actually making an
impact not because they have this need
to be validated on social media that's
right that's right
in fact I follow a lot of people mm-hmm
social media who I don't know but I
value their opinions I enjoy their
analysis I think they have a lot going
for them and I just feel like a better
informed person because of it
right right now let me ask you a
question because you have expertise in
this field and ladies and gentlemen if
you have not read his book doing time
like a spy I would make sure you do I
would make sure you get that book you
have expertise in this field so I mean
you know I want you to you know give us
some sort of uh
we talked about inside baseball here
when I look at what's taking place in
Russia I had my own ideas and thoughts
about why there's been this big push
against Russia and I want you to explain
I'll get into what I think but you're
the guest
tell us if you are if you are if you
have the expertise of a spy what would
you attribute to this push against
Russia this this villain ization of
Russia yeah is it you know is it some
sort of you know quote-unquote false
flag is it some sort of you know
misdirection here at UT what would you
as a you know as a trained CIA officer
say this was about or as a Tracy I
officer I know you know maybe you know a
little bit of some about this answers
are yes and yes no do tell I think I
think the core of this is is entirely
political mm-hmm we need to have a
boogie man we need to have a common
enemy around whom we can rally or
against whom we can rally right and you
know the the the Russians are so easy as
are the Chinese the North Koreans the
Cubans the Iranians mm-hmm
but the Russians you know people
understand Americans understand the
Russians we've been we've been the
enemies of the Russians for a very long
time and so they're easy to they're easy
to bully mm-hmm and they're easy to to
blame for our problems you know I've
been so intrigued by this whole Russia
gate thing and it's because I'm just not
seeing it right no I after I left the
CIA I was the I was the senior
investigator on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee and that's the the
premier prestige Committee on Capitol
Hill running so in order to be a serious
investigator in order to really be taken
seriously by the Congress and by the
media you have to do serious
investigations and so I was always
looking for the facts right sure I had
my own political views but
have to you have to just go where the
facts lead you hmm
so not to take too much of your time but
let's look at this so long
take as much time as you want go ahead
we'll start with Mike Flynn in December
of 2016 after Donald Trump was elected
president Benjamin Netanyahu asked his
UN Ambassador to ask Mike Flynn to ask
the Russians if you can follow this
mm-hmm
itto Barack Obama's Security Council
resolution opposing Israeli settlements
okay
so Flynn went to the Russians and asked
them if they would veto the Russians
said no that was the end of it
now Flynn lied about that to the FBI and
he's had to take a felony plea because
of it mm-hmm but that wasn't Russian
interference that was Israeli
interference mm-hmm but we're not
talking about Israeli interference
mm-hmm
AIPAC the american israel political
action committee is probably the single
most important single wealthiest and
most active lobbying firm in america hmm
it works solely on behalf of the
government of israel yet it is not
registered as a representative of a
foreign government mm-hmm
why is that that's Israeli meddling in
American elections mm-hmm now if you
look at what the Russians have been
accused of they were accused of spending
a hundred thousand dollars on Facebook
ads thousand dollars of that money was
spent after the election was over right
half of the half or 25,000 was spent in
states that were solidly red or solidly
blue so they had no effect on the
election that leaves $25,000 to sway the
u.s. election $25,000 when I was at the
CIA 50,000 was my petty cash that I kept
in my safe for spending money
so if if people think that the Russians
could throw the election for $25,000
that Americans are so stupid and so
gullible as to be influenced by $25,000
worth of Facebook ads you know then
we're in a sorrier shape than most of us
have have previously thought so you know
I'm just not seeing evidence of real
Russian intervention in our elections
now do countries seek to involve
themselves in elections absolutely yes
you have questions probably easily the
Americans and the Chinese and the
British and the French and the Israelis
and everybody else that's what countries
do that is what it de Ghent services do
but if you're going to make an
accusation against the world superpower
an accusation of an international crime
you have to put up and if you can't put
up then you have to shut up all right so
far no one has given us any evidence
real evidence of Russian hacking or
Russian collusion very good now I'm
going to ask you to - to see if you know
I'm on the right track yet I I looked at
this when it happened
I looked at it for three reasons as to
why this happened
I'll start with the to me the left of
the the least consequential ones first a
Hillary Clinton had to be able to
justify to her donors who gave an
exorbitant amount of money to her in
order to win this election election in
2016 that someone had to be the fall guy
for this loss this big loss that came in
2016 this historic loss in 2016 that's
the first thing I saw when I looked at
this that this is why somehow you know
Russia becomes the bad guy the second
thing I looked at was and like I said
you you tell me if I'm if you think I'm
on the wrong track you're not the second
thing I looked at was well Russia has
been a staunch supporter of the Assad
government
in Syria going directly against the US
government and so wouldn't it indeed be
able you be able to justify whatever
military action you take against Russia
or whatever you try to do to against
Russia in that regard that since you've
vilified them as being the one that
stole your election then it's much
easier much easier to justify your
actions against them going for it when
it comes to Syria and thirdly but my
last reason was was that to me because
Obama and the Democratic Party started
this line when he came to Russia gay
was that this was the big payback for
Russia taken in that which know you know
these were the things that came to the
mountain and most does it sound like I'm
on the wrong track here with I think
you're exactly on the right track and
it's more than that I'll add two things
go right it was also for US involvement
in Ukraine where we helped to depose a
government that sought rapprochement
with Russia and replaced it with a
pro-western Pro u.s. Pro NATO right-wing
government the Russians earth the old
Nazi government precisely correct you
know the Russians are panicked at the
notion of of NATO being right they're
literally on on their border and the
other thing is the u.s. is really upset
about Russian activism in the Middle
East when I was still at the CIA
US policy was and this was carried out
mostly by the State Department that US
policy was that we never work with the
Russians in the Middle East
because the goal was to keep the
Russians out of the Middle East we
didn't want there to be two superpowers
in the Middle East we wanted to be the
ones that called the shots and you know
I remember when when the Middle East
peace process was taking off I was
serving in Bahrain which is a little a
little country an island nation in the
Persian Gulf right and and the the
Middle East peace process of course was
multilateral and it included the
Russians well the barrios were hosting
the Middle East peace process talks on
the environment
and they had set up an Environmental
Center there that included Israeli
diplomats so my instructions were to go
to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and
formally invite them to the to the
meeting well because the talks were
multilateral I was supposed to go with
my Russian counterpart and my orders
came from the State Department to not
call the Russian embassy and just to do
it alone and so I did and then of course
I got an angry call from the Russians
saying hey why did you do this this is
supposed to be multilateral we're all
supposed to be a part of this peace
process and what am I supposed to say
I'm sorry we were joking or I'm sorry we
say one thing and then we do another
right but the bottom line was that the
policy was to keep the Russians out and
that policy is consistent to this day
across the board Democratic and
Republican presidents work this is a
national policy not a partisan exactly
now you mention NATO so this sex great
sex ways into a question that it's been
heavy on my mind what is your knowledge
saying that Facebook and Twitter now
says this anti prop law was attached to
the National Defense Authorization Act
back in 2016 Christmas Eve by the way
Merry Christmas of 2016 what is your
view and what is your understanding for
those of us who may not be here to the
Atlantic Council what is your
understanding of their purpose their
role there their agenda oh boy that is
such an important question and it's this
is something that almost no Americans
know or understand the Atlantic Council
and it's not just the Atlantic Council
it's the Council on Foreign Relations
the Hudson Institute the American
Enterprise Institute the the Center for
Progress the Center for democracy I mean
there are so many
so-called think tanks here in the
Washington area that take their funding
from the State Department the Defense
Department defense contractors the CIA
is so there they're biased and what they
end up doing is reinforcing one another
I'll give you an example I'm I guess
technically a journalist and so I'm
registered as a journalist run State
Department and I received the State
Department's morning briefing email
every day and what they do at the State
Department's Office of Public Affairs or
Bureau of Public Affairs is they will
they will refer you to a number
sometimes as many as a half a dozen
different think tanks hmm to see what's
going on that day so they'll say things
like well we're looking at the Middle
East peace process and the Middle East
Institute has a lunch at 12 o'clock and
they're going to talk about Syria and
you should go to that or the Hudson
Institute is going to be talking about
the Chinese naval operations in the
South China Sea at 2 o'clock you should
go to that so what they do is they they
fund these organizations like the
Atlantic Council and it should add to
that NATO also funds the Atlantic
Council right so what they do is they
fund these organizations and then they
refer you back to these organizations
where they can pare it back their policy
to you and make it look like it's it's
independent mm-hmm yeah that it's not
just you getting their position from two
different sides that that here's an
independent think-tank and they're
telling you that our policy is right
well King that think-tank to pare it
back the policy so the whole system is
corrupt the whole system is dishonest
what
what if anything any difference is I
mean D whether it be minor whether you
be major what differences have you seen
in the past you know since Trump was
inaugurated what differences do you see
and how the intelligence agencies run is
there any difference at all well it
depends Nam in terms of differences at
the top hmm yeah of the major
intelligence organizations no because
you've got Mike Pompeo who's a Donald
Trump loyalist riding this guy a you
have Dan Coates who's a lifelong
Republican Party functionary has
Director of National Intelligence
I said Pompey was at the CIA he's a men
at State Department okay Gena Haspel who
is a career CIA professional who owes
her career to Donald Trump net CIA so at
those top most positions no I don't
think that there's really any difference
between this administration and the last
one or even the one before that mm-hmm
that said at the working level yes I
think there's a big difference
I think that the deep state is real
there really is such a thing as the deep
state right I think it seeks to
destabilize this president but at the
same time you know these guys at the CIA
in the senior intelligence service
they've been there for 25 30 35 years
they're not going anywhere right they're
not political appointees their career
run and so they can outweigh this
president right if they like this
president like they didn't like Bill
Clinton and they didn't like Jimmy
Carter they know that he's gonna go
right with two years from now or six
years from now he's gonna go and they're
still gonna be there and so what they do
is they slow roll everything and what I
mean by that is maybe they don't target
that really risky source maybe they
don't begin that really risky operation
and maybe they don't work hard to
provide the finest analysis
maybe they just go through the motions
and just wait until this president is
gone and the making of a the president
that they like and that likes them and
let me add something else too about
Barack Obama okay
he used to ask me this question all the
time like why was Obama as staunchly Pro
CIA as he was I mean Obama gave the CIA
literally anything and everything that
it asked for drones and webbing special
operations and you name it by god the
CIA was allowed to do it mm-hmm the
reason is because the CIA loves new
presidents that have no intelligence
experience right and it's because the
day after the election the
president-elect is entitled to a PDB
briefing President Lee briefed run and
that's when you get the most highly
classified information available so when
you see your first blue border report or
black border report where you're six
levels above top secret and the briefer
says mr. president-elect let me tell you
about all the cool things we're doing
around the world
well they've sucked you right in we've
routed you right that's exactly what
they seek to do they seek to make you
one of the guys and once you're one of
the guys you're gonna let them have and
do anything they want but they never
expected Donald Trump to get elected
mm-hmm and then they never expected to
get caught spying on the Trump campaign
we've had admissions I mean there's sort
of backhanded admissions but admissions
by the FBI that that's exactly what they
were doing hmm
you know FISA warrants on Carter page in
the name but they put a source inside
the campaign to report back to the FBI
and that's just unheard of it's
unprecedented
and remind us John what President were
you prosecuted under you know that's a
yeah that's a great question
it was Barack Obama that prosecuted me
and not just me but seven other national
security whistleblowers you know II D
the the Espionage Act was written in
1917 hmm fix that German spies during
the the First World War
mm-hmm this law is so old that it
doesn't even mention the term classified
information because it's written 40
years before the classification system
was even invented right it mentions
National Defense Information but it
doesn't define it it says that a person
is guilty of espionage if he provides
national defense information to any
person not entitled to receive it that
is so broadly written that I believe it
to be unconstitutional mm-hmm that's
really nobody has had standing to
challenge it to the Supreme Court and
certainly Congress doesn't have the guts
to do anything because you're not the
wind votes by challenging the Espionage
Act of all things and so you know it was
inevitable that we were going to get a
president at some point I regret and
lament the fact that it was Barack Obama
who was going to use the Espionage Act
as a political weapon mm-hmm you're
doing 1917 in 2009 three Americans were
charged with espionage for cooperating
with the media mm-hmm just during the
Obama administration eight of us almost
three times the number of all previous
presidents combined eight of us were
prosecuted by the Obama administration
the constitutional lawyer yeah
the constitutional lawyer yes a champion
the champion of the left
you know I Eve din the whole Hope and
Change thing I really did I volunteered
on the campaign I voted for Obama mmm I
I took my kids to the inauguration to
see this you know historic event
and it all turned out to be just a big
lie yeah it's a book that was written by
Mark Halperin and John Holliman yeah
call called double down about the 2012
election it was a it was a sequel to
their book on the 2008 election and
President Obama agreed to sit for an
interview for DoubleDown and he said two
things that were just chilling mm-hmm he
said very matter-of-factly I never said
I was a liberal exactly yeah no and when
you think about it that's true
we believed he was a liberal but he
never said he was he wasn't mm-hmm the
other thing is he was talking about the
drone program and he said I never had
any idea that I would be so good at
killing people yeah oh yeah that was
chilling oh my when you the last month
of the George W Bush administration bush
killed two people with the use of a
drone in his last month mm-hmm his last
month as president he killed 424 people
with drones if that doesn't put things
into perspective I don't know what does
hmm as we've been talking we get we
received some breaking news nikki Haley
you an ambassador of resigned yeah so
what are your thoughts on that and and
what does this what is that a sign of I
mean this is before the midterms and
your UN Ambassador resigns what's what's
up with that I have a couple of thoughts
on this mm-hmm
nikki Haley was simply not taken
seriously around the world and she was
she was loved in in the Trump White
House mm-hmm and in the State Department
among the political people but she just
was not a serious ambassador she had
literally no foreign policy experience
with that said I recently spoke with a
very senior Republican Party official
who was also a senior member of the
Trump campaign this is a nationally
known figure and he told me an
absolutely fascinating story
he said that Henry McMaster
who is now the governor of South
Carolina was the lieutenant governor
during the Trump campaign and Henry
McMaster was the first elected official
in America to endorse Donald Trump
so when Trump won the election the
campaign went to McMaster and said what
do you want what do you want for a
reward and McMaster said I want to be
governor of South Carolina well Nikki
Haley was already the governor of South
Carolina hmm so you need to get nikki
Haley out well what is nikki Haley want
Nikki Haley wants to be President of the
United States and what's holding her
back is that she had no foreign policy
so she said sure she'll resign as
governor of South Carolina if she can
either have UN Ambassador or Secretary
of State well Trump already had ideas
for Secretary of State
usually a Christie Tillerson Petraeus he
wasn't gonna make her Secretary of State
but he was willing to make her
ambassador to the United Nations so she
took that job which prepares her now for
2024 and McMaster became governor of
South Carolina
so why she resigned this early in the
term doesn't make sense to me I think
she really was not effectual at the
United Nations and she probably wants to
make some money before she eventually
runs for president but in the long term
I think that's the plan now she did say
today after her meeting with the
president that she was going to campaign
for Republicans in the midterm elections
which any potential presidential
candidate would do because that's how
you collect political chips exactly and
second she said that she would campaign
with the president in 2020 well that's
going to continue to raise her profile
and make her appealing or more appealing
to Republican Party activists in advance
of 2024 I think she knows exactly what
she's doing
except when it came to being a UN
Ambassador Lee clueless oh my goodness
you know any sort of intellectual
curiosity no sort of it's probably oh
yeah policy have to work none of that at
all none of that at all well John I
thank you for your insights today I mean
they have been extremely illuminating
and we appreciate all the hard work you
have done and all the hard work you are
doing I look forward to having it all
for the fifth time sometime soon and
thank you for what you do this is really
great yeah thank you thank you ladies
and gentlemen this was
John Kiriakou
if you got the chance as I said before
get the book doing time like a spy how
the CIA taught me to survive and thrive
in